Perry Harlock - Lead Front End Web Developer

www.phwebs.co.uk

Living in Kent, working in London.

Connect | linkedIn, Twitter, GitHub

E | perry@phwebs.co.uk

T | 07876 572123

Personal Profile

I'm a self-motivated and experienced front end developer currently designing and heading up the front end magic for the UK's leading venue booking website. http://hirespace.com

I have several years of experience in HTML(5), CSS(3), LESS, Sass, XSLT, XML, jQuery, Javascript, Photoshop, GitHub, Agile, Twitter Bootstrap. I'm renowned for fast HTML and CSS coding, accuracy and attention to detail as well as awesome interpersonal skills and a relaxed temperament.

Skills Summary

HTML(5), XHTML, CSS(3), LESS, Sass, W3C Standards and Accessibility Aware, Responsive Web Design, Cross browser compatibility, Progressive enhancement, Photoshop, Web Design, GitHub, Javascript / jQuery

Career History

May 2014 - Present

Hire Space – http://hirespace.com Lead Front End Web Developer

Lead front end web developer for the UK's leading venue booking website, Hire Space.

HTML, CSS(3), Web Design, Javascript / jQuery.

I am currently enjoying re-designing and re-building the current public facing web site (hirespace.com) in addition to refining and adding functionality to the booking system used by customers.

Making the site responsive and friendlier to smaller devices is one of my main.

December 2012 - April 2014

Nature Publishing Group - www.nature.com Front End Web Developer

HTML, CSS(3) and design plus some Javascript / jQuery for leading scientific and medical information publisher Nature.

My work consisted of front end design and development of an internal tool to give greater visibility of the huge amount of data being stored on the new triplestore.

I was also responsible for the design and front end code for accessibility tool pa11y www.pa11y.org

November 2011 - December 2012

BraveNewTalent - www.bravenewtalent.com
Front End Web Developer

HTML, CSS(3) and design plus some Javascript / jQuery in a fast moving agile development environment for the BNT Talent Community Platform website.

My initial responsibility was for the redesign and build of the Enterprise section of the site. Working from BDD's and wireframes I coded the HTML and CSS.

I then worked across the whole site ensuring that our HTML and CSS was clean, concise and well structured, utilising Less to make our CSS as modular and re-useable as possible and model it on the 'OO' methodology of CSS.

March 2011 - November 2011

Assertis Ltd - www.mytrainticket.co.uk

Front End Web Developer

Development of the front end for the MyTrainTicket site and other white label sites for third parties including Travel Supermarket and Northern Rail.

Taking Photoshop / Fireworks designs and hand-coding XHTML, CSS (with a helping hand from Sass), XSLT, Javascript / jQuery.

Responsible for molding the strategy of front end development practices including the choice of tools, standards and methods used within Assertis.

My experience with Sass led to a case study I submitted being printed in the December issue of .net magazine in December 2011.

February 2008 - February 2011

Eonic Ltd - www.eonic.co.uk

Front End Web Developer / Company Trainer

Responsible for developing W3C compliant websites from a layered PSD utilising XHTML, XSLT, CSS and jQuery / Javascript combined with an in-house developed CMS.

Developed as company trainer responsible for training clients on the use of the in-house CMS and to give advice on best practices for updating their newly developed web sites

September 2007 - Present

Freelance / Positive Change Creations Ltd Freelance Web Developer / Designer

I decided to master a more communications based technology and took a role as a Freelance Junior Web Developer with Positive Change Creations.

I received basic training in .NET 2.0 and SQL Server 2005 and also completed work in HTML 4.0 (XHTML compliant) and CSS.

It was at this time that I also started as a freelancer offering web sites to small businesses to gain experience and knowledge of XHTML, CSS and jQuery and to build a portfolio.

August 1988 - September 2007

Various roles including HR Systems Support Analyst, IT Systems Support and just for a change Martial Arts Instructor.

Education

Tunbridge Wells Grammar School for Boys, Tunbridge Wells

O Levels: English Grade B, Maths Grade B, Engineerig Drawing Grade C

CSE: Physics Level 3

Interests

When I'm not coding I can usually be found on my beloved mountain bike in a multitude of muddy, wet locations trying very hard not to fall off (with only a moderate success rate).

I love progressive house, electronic and most dance music in general to the point of nerdiness.